# Thomas Nieuwland

J 0431685686 — 

thomas nieuwland19@gmail.com — 

tomnieuw.land — 

Thomas Nieuwland

About Me

I'm a 24 year old Fullstack Engineer with a passion for back end development, tooling, automation and cloud computing. I love to muck around with all sorts of weird and wonderful tech, no matter how bleeding edge. I'm also an avid video game enthusiast who loves a good book as well as a bit of a music snob, who likes to mess around with a DJ controller in his spare time.

# **E**xperience

## **Grok Learning**

Mid Software Engineer

**Duties** 

- Design and implementation of features and functionality for the Grok Learning platform
- Creation of educational content for use on the Grok Learning platform
- Assisting in project management, triaging tickets, simple scrum master work

# Accomplishments

- Spearheaded upcoming conversion of database from Javascript to Typescript
- Implemented university examination functionality as well as university rubric based marking into the platform
- Major refactor of multiple core objects that are key to Grok functionality

#### **Rotor Studios**

Core Tech and Pipeline Developer Mid Fullstack Developer Junior Fullstack Developer Duties ♥ Sydney, Australia
April 2019 - December 2019
December 2018 - April 2019
December 2017 - December 2018

Sydney, Australia

December 2019 - Present

- Design, implementation and maintenance of core internal architecture as well as various company internal tools
- Development and maintenance of a heavily used asset distribution API
- Development and maintenance of multiple web based product configuration tools

### Accomplishments

- Design and implementation of internal analytics and tracking framework
- Design and implementation of core internal database to be used as a source of truth for the company
- Batch image processing pipeline utilising AWS Lambda, which massively reduced both time and cost for the company

## Australian Pacific College

Digital Solutions and Resources Support Officer

St George & Sutherland Community College

Computer Science Tutor

 ♥ Sydney, Australia

 December 2016 - December 2017

♥ Sydney, Australia
December 2015 - February 2017

# **Education**

**Bachelor of Computer Science** 

Majoring in Software Engineering

**Higher School Certificate** 

**♥** University of Wollongong 2015 - 2018

♥ St John Bosco College 2008 - 2014 I have experience in the following areas

- Python 2/3
  - Django
  - Flask
  - Celery
  - DRF
- Javascript (Node & ES6)
- Typescript
- C++

- Databases
  - PostgreSQL
  - MariaDB
  - OracleDB
  - MongoDB
  - CouchDB
  - Elasticsearch
  - ElastiCache
  - Redis
- $\bullet$  Docker & Docker Compose
- $\bullet$  RabbitMQ

- $\bullet$  AWS
  - Lambda
  - Kinesis
  - Aurora
  - DynamoDB
  - EC2
  - ECS
  - SNS
  - SQS